Muhammad ALJUNIED

FREELANCE DEVELOPER

Mobile: +65 9380 8439

Email: muhammadaliunied@u.nus.edu

Skype: muhammadaljunied

URL: muhammadaljunied.github.io



Personal Statement

Internship Objective

To obtain an internship as a Software Development Intern where my strong problem solving, and analytical skills will be utilized.

About me

I am a second year Computer Engineering undergraduate with 6 years of experience developing software on the .NET platform as well as some static website deployments. While undertaking my Diploma in Information Technology (Technical school equivalent), I began freelancing as a software developer, working on static websites and simple to moderately complex desktop applications.

No matter what age I imagine myself at, I always picture myself developing something, in both software and hardware, though my first love will always be software. I am a strong believer of quality work, with as little compromise. I prioritize clear communication when working in a team or for a client. Engage me in conversation and you'll find that I am approachable and smile a whole lot when talking, or so I have been told! The musings of a good philosophical debate or topics on neuroscientific discoveries, I find thoroughly enjoyable. As a final note, though I have spent much time in the development of desktop applications, I am very keen to work on a web based or mobile platform for a change of scenery.

Work Experiences/Projects

Since I was 16, I was involved with my family-run startup providing printout of photos at event. As the print manager, I created and refined the physical processes involving the printing of photos to eliminate error, maintain quality and improve throughput. Over the course of 3 years, we had unparalleled throughput of photos, handling events of upwards to 30,000 people across 3 days.

In my third year of study undertaking my Diploma, I developed a Cheque Printing solution for a non-profit organization which disbursed money to students in need. Prior to my solution, these cheques were handwritten by the admin staff. This solution is still in use today. Challenging myself, I attempted to pursue a corporate client in the Building Management sector by working with a student investigating the benefits of consolidating building management resources into a central location as part of her Final Year Project. With her insights into the processes and norms of the industry, I developed a working prototype which the stakeholders of the case study company were impressed by and wanted to see more of. However, they could not commit to any form of remuneration for any further development. I then embarked on a second internship at LOKAL*SOCIAL, a startup in Jakarta, to further work on their Android Application. Upon returning, I served 2 years in the Singapore Police Force as an Excel Developer and a Staff Assistant. I developed macros to automate time-consuming administrative tasks as well as processing large datasets to flag out inconsistencies. During my 2-year enlistment till present day, I develop for Tagronauts, an Instagram printing start-up based in Singapore. Some notable projects I've worked on include a Live Instagram Lucky Draw System, automation solutions to streamline business processes and running operations when the founder is not available.

Some projects I work on during my free, albeit little time, includes a Universal Wireless File Transmitter for DSLRs on a Raspberry Pi, a Business Management Application for an Automobile Workshop in Singapore as well as an end-to-end solution for award ceremonies, from the RSVP to registration and the award ceremony.

Education

Aug 2016 - Present	National University of Singapore BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (HONOURS) IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING	Singapore
Apr 2010 – Apr 2013	(Course details in Appendix A) Temasek Polytechnic (Technical Certificate Equivalent) DIPLOMA WITH MERIT, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY	Singapore

Work Experience

SEP 2014 - DEC 2017 Tagronauts

Singapore

DEVELOPER/MANAGER

Tagronauts is an On-Site Photo Printing start-up that delivers the highest throughput of photos printed by accelerating the printing process using software and automation.

- Developed and deployed software for client events
- Developed MS Word Macros to streamline business processes
- Execute operations on-site.

DEC 2014 - NOV 2015

Police National Service Department STAFF ASSISTANT (PLANNING DIVISION)

Singapore

Served as the Staff Assistant to the Assistant Director of the Planning Division and Planning Officer (Police).

- Reviewed and updated 3 Standard Operating Procedures for National Service Police Officers.
- Developed automation macros to improve operational efficiency of various divisions.

JAN 2014 - DEC 2014

Ministry of Home Affairs

Singapore

EXCEL DEVELOPER (HUMAN TRANSFORMATION OFFICE)

National Service at the Ministry of Home Affairs under the Home Team's Flag (Police).

- Developed Excel automation macros to streamline existing business processes.
- Developed and deployed 20 projects across several law enforcement agencies.
- Headed data consolidation, processing and filtration for records dating back 10 years.

SEP 2013 - NOV 2013 OCT 2012 - JAN 2013

LOKAL*SOCIAL

Jakarta

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

LOKAL*SOCIAL was a start-up in Jakarta that aimed to break into the food listing business with plans to pioneer restaurant bookings in the Jakarta.

- Designed and developed a native Android application.
- Conducted testing in locations of high human traffic to measure overall data usage and speed.
- Executed marketing campaigns at Universities to garner users.

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

APR 2013	Anugerah Mendaki 2013 AWARD RECEIPIENT	Singapore
	Bursary for Academic Excellence (Polytechnic/Diploma)	
APR 2011 – JUN 2013	Microsoft Student Partner (MSP)	Singapore
	TECHNICAL REPRESENTATIVE	
	 Conducted a course on Azure Cloud Service with 120 participants. 	
	 The course covered deployment of ASP.NET Applications Azure. 	
	 Provided technical support up to three weeks after. 	
APR 2012 - APR 2013	Temasek Polytechnic Directors List AWARD RECEIPIENT	Singapore
	 Top 10% of the cohort for AY 11/12 and AY 12/13 	

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java Java (Android) C C++ (Ardunio) C# (.NET) XAML (.NET) VB (.NET) VBA Python	Intermediate Basic Basic Intermediate Proficient Intermediate Proficient Proficient Basic
Web	HTML, CSS PHP Javascript	Basic Basic Basic
Database	MySQL MSSQL	Intermediate Intermediate
Hardware Design	Verilog Vivado 2016	Basic Basic
Microcontrollers	Arduino Raspberry Pi	Intermediate Basic
Office	MS Word/Powerpoint/Access + VBA MS Excel + VBA	Intermediate/Basic Intermediate/Proficient
Multimedia	Adobe Photoshop CC	Intermediate

Language Proficiency

Spoken	nglish – fluent; Malay – Basic	
Written	English - competent; Malay- Basic	

APPENDIX A

Degree: Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Computer Engineering

Course Description (List of relevant modules)	Status
Introduction to Computer Engineering	Completed
Data Structures and Algorithms I	Completed
Introductory Mathematics	Completed
Fundamentals of Physics II	Completed
Electrical Engineering	Completed
Critical Thinking And Writing	Completed
Introductory Mathematics	Completed
Discrete Structures	Completed
Mathematics I	Completed
Digital Fundamentals	Completed
Electronic Circuits	Completed
Asking Questions	Completed
Real-Time Operating Systems	In-Progress
Programming for Computer Interfaces	In-Progress
Cyber Security	In-Progress
Physics IIE	In-Progress
Linear Algebra With Differential Equations	In-Progress
Differential Equations for Engineering	In-Progress